在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
震荡波 我以为你已经在塞博特恩阵亡了
Shockwave... I thought you'd perished on Cybertron.
接入器没能取得任何关于汽车人行踪的新信息
The patch failed to yield any new information on the whereabouts of the Autobots.
不管在哪里 我都听得出这引擎声！
I' d know the hum of that engine anywhere.
老千！
Jackie!
我们不能就这么放弃了！
We can't just give up!
那么你告诉我 我们还能做什么！
Then tell me what we can do!
我们知道红蜘蛛在其单独行动期间 使用过环陆桥
We know Starscream had access to a groundbridge.
他利用了霸天虎的废弃飞船 先驱号
He'd clearly been using the Harbinger.
那上面可能装满了各种塞博特恩资源
It could be full of Cybertronian tech.
物资再多又能怎么样
Resources won't be of much use
如果没有人来…领导我们
not without someone to lead us.
…铸锤
The Forge.
如果你有了卓天越之锤 就能自我修复了
If you had the Forge, you could fix yourself up!
来见见通天晓
Meet Ultra Magnus.
很荣幸向您展示 我的君王
I present to you, my liege
终极汽车人猎手！
the ultimate Autobot hunter.
巨狰狞！
A Predacon.
他们不是在史前塞博特恩就已经灭绝了吗！
They've been extinct since the beginning of Cybertronian history.
的确
Indeed.
但你眼前的样本是在实验室中培育的
But the specimen you see before you was bred in the laboratory
是由我在塞博特恩挖掘出的化石克隆而来
cloned from fossilized remains, which I discovered on Cybertron.
震荡波 能再次见到你的旷世杰作令我非常愉悦
Shockwave, it does my spark good to see you once again tampering with creation.
主人 请不要靠得太近！
Master, please! Keep your distance!
无须紧张 这头野兽已完全在我的掌控之中
No need for alarm. The beast is completely under my control.
好个原始而雄壮的力量！
Such primal magnificence.
这是千斤顶受审时溢出的汽车人能量液样本
A sample of Energon, from Wheeljack, spilled during the Autobot's failed interrogation.
那么 开始狩猎吧…
Let the hunt begin.
伙计们 把那些破烂轰上天我完全没意见
Guys, you know I'm all for blowin' the scrap outta stuff
但炸平一个虎子的能量矿\N对我们重组乐队或干掉威震天有帮助吗？
but what does flattening a Decepticon mine have to do with getting the band back together and taking down Megatron?
答案很简单 这里被引爆时一定是火光冲天
Simple. When we light up this place, the blast'll be big and unmistakable.
五百公里内的汽车人\N都会注意到爆炸的光芒并尽快赶来的
Any Autobot within 500 klicks will see the sky glowin' with Energon, and come runnin'.
那就动手吧！
Then bring the rain.
主机已经运转起来了
Mainframe's up and running.
不过我需要你帮忙破译它的操作代码
But I'll need help hacking the operating codes.
就算环陆桥能够正常运转
Even if the groundbridge proves functional
无法锁定其他汽车人的坐标也是枉然
it will be next to worthless without a means of pinpointing the current locations of our compatriots.
动动脑子 大黄蜂
Use your head, Bumblebee.
如果霸天虎能追踪汽车人的信号
If the Decepticons had the ability to track Autobot signals
那我们早就被威震天一网打尽了
we'd have all been at Megatron's mercy here on Earth a long time ago.
唉…功亏一篑
Ah... Back where we started.
未必 如果我能调整这里的信息频率
But not if I can reconfigure these Decepticon frequencies.
或许我们能够使用虎子的通讯链
At the very least, we may be able to access their comm-link.
塞博特恩沦陷以后 就没人再见过你
No one's seen or heard from you since Cybertron went dark.
你是怎么到达地球的？
How did you find your way to Earth?
士兵 虽然我们已不在塞博特恩
Soldier, we may not be on Cybertron
但是军事条例依旧有效
but military protocol remains.
很抱歉 长官
My apologies, Sir.
长官？
Sir?
知会本地生命形态注意他的语气
Advise the native life-form to watch its tone as well.
什么？这谁啊？
What? Who is this guy?
通天晓是塞博特恩战争时期 擎天柱的首席副官
Ultra Magnus was Optimus' key Lieutenant during the war back on Cybertron.
极端教条主义 千万别顶撞他
Very "by the book". Just go with it.
对于你的问题
As for your broader question
我的经历和其他汽车人大同小异
my story is that of all Autobots since the exodus.
在被迫撤离家园以后 我徘徊在宇宙中搜寻同胞
I wandered the spaceways in search of others
但仅有少数人能够与我重聚
reuniting with some
更多的时候我只能眼看着他们惨遭霸天虎的毒手
often only to see them fall at the hands of the Decepticons.
直到你接收到终极之光并跟随它来到这里
Until you detected the Omega beam, and followed it here.
如果你指的是由塞博特恩发射出的高强度能量束
If you are referring to the massive energy burst originating from Cybertron
那么你说对了
that would be affirmative.
当到达这个星球时 我发现它已然遭到霸天虎的入侵
Upon my arrival, it became evident that this planet had been invaded.
但我的扫描器也同时探测到了多个汽车人的生命信号
My scanners also detected Autobot life signals
而你们是距离我最近的
yours being in closest proximity to my position.
多个信号？
Signals? As in plural?
长官
Sir.
总数五名
Five total.
但我们有七名汽车人
Out of seven.
杰克 别一下子把事情往最坏处想
Jack, that doesn't necessarily mean what you're thinking.
没被探测到的信号 很可能是被什么东西屏蔽了
Autobot signals can't be detected when they're shielded.
小堡垒建得蛮舒适的嘛 威震天
Cozy little place you built for yourself, Megatron.
找锤子估计要花些时间了
Finding the Forge in there may take awhile.
或者说…
Then, again
你仍会把贵重的东西藏在你的老地方…
maybe you still keep your valuables in the usual place.
我不会让你失望的 擎天柱
I won't let you down, Optimus.
啥 我小题大做？
I'm sorry, "overreacting?"
你说得倒轻巧 击倒！
Easy for you to say, Knockout.
这里可没人想抢你的职位
Nobody here wants your post.
而我就不同了 我身处所有霸天虎都梦寐以求的位置上
I, on the other hand, hold the most coveted position within the Decepticon ranks.
不管震荡波嘴上怎么说
And no matter what he may claim
但我知道他心里一直在盘算着篡我的权！
I know that Shockwave is plotting to usurp me!
当他给威震天陛下展示那头野兽时
Did you see the smug look in his eye
你瞧他那副小人得志的嘴脸！
when he unveiled that vile beast to lord Megatron?
我可不怕你 丑八怪！
You don't scare me, ugly.
你在这儿呢 美人儿！
Hello, beautiful.
炸药放置完毕
Munitions planted.
好戏这就开场了
Let's get this party started.
有人来了！
Company.
威震天？
Megatron?
不 是个更大的
Nah. Bigger.
我不记得铁桶头的马戏团里有这个小丑
And I don't remember seeing that move in buckethead's repertoire.
龙？
A dragon?
虎子什么时候弄到一条龙？
Where'd the 'Cons get a dragon?
- 龙是什么？\N- 龙是什么？
- What's a dragon?\N- What's a dragon?
会飞会喷火的大蜥蜴！
Giant flying fire-breathing lizard.
隔板 你没事吧？
Bulkhead, you okay?
小心烫手 我可是刚出炉的
Easy, I may be hot to the touch.
它怎么不追我们了？
Why isn't it coming after us?
怪物 找我呢？
Lookin' for me, beast?
老子在此！
I'm right here.
我们需要更强大的火力！
We're gonna need more firepower!
那你算找对人了！
Good thing I know just where to find some!
敌军来袭！
Incoming!
是汽车人！
Autobots!
这下还不活埋了它
And the walls came tumblin' down.
没错！闷死那条该死的龙！
Yes! Snuff the tragic dragon!
这下玩完了！
We're toast.
我们的人？
One of ours?
是又怎样？
Does it matter?
- 杰克！\N- 阿尔茜！
- Jack!\N- Arcee!
神子 我喘不过气了
Miko. Can't breathe.
真是阿弱！
Weakling.
谢谢你的援手
Thanks for the save.
要谢就谢指挥官吧
Thank the Commander.
战士们
Soldiers.
是你？
You?
通天晓？很荣幸见到您
Ultra Magnus? It's an honor.
要说 很荣幸见到您 “长官”！
It's an honor, Sir.
是我制造的大爆炸把你们引来的吧
Guess blowin' that mine made us pretty easy to spot.
通天晓已经追踪到你们的信号了
Ultra Magnus already had a bead on your signals
还有我们的
and ours.
介不介意解释一下那只跟屁虫到底是什么东西？
Care to tell us what exactly's nipping at our tailpipes?
我们觉得那是一只机器龙
We think it's a robot dragon.
或者是某种塞博特恩爬行动物
Or a Cybertronian reptile.
全员注意！
Brace yourselves.
那家伙就在我们头顶
It's right on top of us.
又有何贵干？ 威震天“陛下”
What is it now, lord Megatron?
福勒探员 我是救护车
Agent Fowler, it's Ratchet!
救护车 杰克在哪儿？和你在一起吗？
Ratchet? Where's Jack? Is he with you?
不 他没和我在一起
No, he is not.
听着 我们时间有限
Listen, we don't have much time.
我正冒着无法估算的巨大风险和你联系
I have taken a tremendous, yet calculated, risk in contacting you.
希望虎子们没有疯狂地监控自己的通讯系统
Hopefully, the Decepticons are not monitoring their own frequencies as closely as they no doubt are those of the humans.
我现在把我们当前的坐标发送给你…
I am transmitting our current coordinates.
什么？
What?
救护车 你有其他人的消息吗？
Ratchet, have you heard from anyone else?
擎天柱怎么样了？
What about Prime?
是汽车人的飞船
It's one of ours!
拉夫！
Raf!
这丫头的劲儿不小吧？
Girl's got a grip, doesn't she?
你们都还活着！
You're alive.
通天晓！
Ultra Magnus?
医官
Doctor.
您一定大失所望吧 主人
What a grave disappointment this must be for you, master.
而更糟的是
And to make matters worse
由于巨狰狞言语不能 我们无法得知它为何失败得如此彻底
because it cannot speak, we have no way of knowing why the Predacon failed so miserably.
可怜的生物 又蠢又哑…
Poor, mute, mindless creature.
新喷涂看起来不错嘛 小蜂
New paint job looks good, Bee.
看来你很能自娱自乐嘛
At least you had something to work with.
如果换我的话 我一定会选粉色！
If I reversed my colors, I'd be pink.
我仍需进一步调校通信链 让它兼容汽车人的频率
The communications link needs further calibration to be compatible with Autobot frequencies.
但环陆桥已经可以正常运转了
The groundbridge, however, is fully operational.
这样逃跑就方便多了 等那只机器龙把我们当早餐吃的时候
That would've come in handy when robo-dragon was trying to eat us for breakfast.
这个星球的土著都这样目无纪律吗？
The indigenous population of this planet, do they all display the same disregard for authority?
不 基本上只有神子而已
No. Mostly just Miko.
不 别开枪！
No! Don't shoot!
那是福勒 他是我们这边的！
It's Fowler. He's with us!
没事了 妈妈 我很好
It's okay, mom. I'm fine.
你的家人很安全
Your families are safe.
福勒探员已经确保贾斯帕被及时疏散了
Agent Fowler saw to it that Jasper was evacuated in time.
通天晓所能识别的信号都在这里了
The only signals Ultra Magnus was able to isolate are standing right here.
可能他的扫描器出故障了
Maybe his scanner's faulty.
这么说 烟幕小子仍然下落不明
So the kid's unaccounted for.
当虎子进攻时 烟幕被环陆桥传送走了
Smokescreen bridged out unaccompanied.
只有擎天柱知道目的地
Only Optimus knows where.
当时擎天柱留下断后
And Optimus remained behind
他破坏了环陆桥 以确保每个人都安全撤离
to destroy the groundbridge, to ensure that everyone else... made it to safety.
我…亲眼见到基地被摧毁
I watched the base go down.
没有任何人或东西走出来
No one or thing walked out of there.
或许只是我们没看到
Not that we could see.
即使擎天柱幸存下来了
Even if Prime survived
我们也不能在这里坐等他的出现
I'm not sure we can afford to wait for him to show up.
尤其是威震天正趾高气昂地守在他的黑山老窝
Not with Megatron holding our planet hostage
并将我们整个星球挟为人质
from his high and mighty perch at Darkmount.
我倾向于本地生命形态的意见
I would be inclined to agree with the native life-form.
我们必须阻止威震天
We must stop Megatron
无论擎天柱在与不在
with or without Optimus Prime.
擎天柱
Optimus!
我拿到卓天越之锤了
I have The Forge.
你可以用它来修复自己！
You can use it to repair yourself!
这并非我让你取回这个圣物的本意
That is not the reason I had you retrieve the relic.
什么？我不明白
What? I don't understand.
卓天越之锤的力量 并非无穷无尽
The power of the Forge is not unlimited.
它的能量已接近干涸
Its energy has already begun to ebb.
它的能量是弱了些 那有什么关系！
So it's running low, who cares?
只要能把你治好就足够了！
All we need is enough juice to get you back into fighting shape!
它残余的能量必须用于修复终极之锁
Whatever power remains must be used to rebuild the Omega lock
以复苏塞博特恩
to restore Cybertron.
但那就意味着…
But that would mean...
我们种族的延续比我们任何一员的生命都更为重要…
The fate of all our kind is more vital... than that of any one of us.
…也包括我在内
... Including me.
我们必须竭尽所能 以推翻威震天的统治
We must do everything in our power to ensure Megatron's downfall
而此事只能智取
but we will need to be smart about it.
喔 是谁让这个垫肩男当家的？
Whoa, who put shoulderpads in command?
临时当家而已
Temporary command.
通天晓是唯一合乎逻辑的人选
Ultra Magnus is the only logical choice.
他曾在擎天柱麾下受训
He was trained by Optimus
并在塞博特恩之战时一直担任领导职位
and served as his commanding officer throughout the War For Cybertron.
如果没有其他人提出反对意见的话
Now, unless there is any further objection
战士们 跟我来
soldier, please, follow me.
遵命 头儿
Aye aye, Cap'n.
汽车人们
Autobots.
挑件趁手的家伙吧！
Take your pick.
现在你合我胃口了
Now you're speaking my language
长官！
Sir.
擎天柱 卓天越之锤是领袖的圣物
Optimus, the Forge is a relic of the Primes.
没有领袖 没有您 我们无法用它复苏塞博特恩！
We can't use it to restore Cybertron, not without a Prime. Not without you.
会有一位新领袖站出来的！
There will be a new Prime.
我们先把您治好 同时干掉威震天 然后再操心新领袖吧
You can worry about that after we get you patched up, and we take down Megatron.
新领袖诞生的时刻已然到来！
The time for a new leader is upon us.
以我火种之名
In my spark...
我坚信他此刻就站在我的面前！
I believe that leader... stands before me right now.